this comes this will be the last lecture
这来自这将是最后一次演讲
on machine level programming we call it
在机器语言的 我们叫它
advanced topics but think of it more as
高级的主题，但认为它更像
miscellaneous topics and I think most to
杂项议题，我认为最 让
you of course you know that your bomb
你当然知道 你们的炸弹
labs are due tonight
实验室是由于今晚
so you most here probably well into that
所以你在这里最可能以及 成
or hopefully through it and then at
或希望通过它，然后在
midnight tonight the next web will come
今晚午夜下一个web会
out which is called a tack lab and there
出被称为粘性的实验室，有
is a recitation about that yesterday but
是关于昨天朗诵但
this is a lab that are new to the course
这是这样一个实验室，是新 课程
it's a similar to one that we used to
这是一个类似于一个 我们用来
use at this point in the course but it's
在这一点上在使用过程中使用，但它的
been updated and changed in significant
被更新，并在显著改变
ways so we're actually when you have
方式，所以我们实际上是当你有
labs like we do in this course with this
像我们的实验室在这个过程中和这事
many students there's a lot of things
很多学生有很多的东西
that go can go wrong so we're going to
是去可以去错了 ，所以我们要
keep a close eye on on how things are
密切关注 的事情是如何
going but I'd encourage you you only
打算 ，但我 只 建议您在
have a week and a half to do this next
有一个半星期要做到这一点 未来
web to get started soon and partly by
网络得到很快，部分由开始
having some people start sooner you'll
有一些人开始越早，你会
start breaking things for us that we can
开始摔东西给我们 ，我们可以
track down so today what we'll talk
所以今天我们将讨论追查
about is a couple like I said it's
大约是一对夫妇就像我说的
miscellaneous topics but important
杂项议题，但重要
topics one is to sort of where what does
话题之一是排序的哪里是什么呢
the memory look like when you're running
内存的外观，当你运行像
x86 64 programs the other is a very
86 64周的方案，另一个是一个 非常
important topic on security
对安全的重要课题
vulnerability called buffer overflows
漏洞称为缓冲区溢出
and in fact at a collab we'll be
而事实上，在一个协同合作，我们会
precisely exploiting those security
正是利用这些安全
vulnerabilities and then we'll look at
漏洞，然后我们将看看
Union so far you've looked at arrays and
联盟到目前为止，你已经看了阵列和
structs and how they're organized and I
结构以及他们是如何组织的，我
want to compare that to unions so let's
想比较， 为工会让我们
talk about memory then as I said at the
说说内存，则正如我 在 说
beginning early in the course
在课程开始初期
conceptually a memory is just a big
从概念上来说，记忆是 只是一个大
array of bytes and that the view of this
的字节和该阵列的该视图
machine level programmer even though
机器级的程序员，即使
it's not the actual implementation
它不是 实际执行
there's a whole part that we'll talk
有一个整体的一部分，我们将讨论
about later in the course of this is
关于后来 在这个过程中是
called virtual memory
所谓虚拟内存
this organization is very simple
这个组织是非常简单的
organization but the underlying
组织，而是底层
implementation is this complex
实现这个复杂
management of various different memory
各种不同的内存管理
types from disk memories to solid state
从磁盘存储器固态类型
disks and to what's called DRAM which
磁盘到什么叫做DRAM 其中
stands for dynamic Ram the when you buy
代表动态RAM的，当你购买
memory for your processor is DRAM oh so
内存为您的处理器是DRAM 哦，这么
as you know in x86 64 we're working with
如您在x86的64知道我们有工作
machines that nominally are have
机器， 名义上是有
addresses can be up to 64 bits long and
地址可以 是高达 64位长，并
if you work out the numbers remember I
如果你的工作 号码记住我
told you at the beginning of the course
告诉你在课程开始
you can estimate how big a number like
您可以估算有多大了 许多像
to the 64 is by remembering that a
到64是通过记住一个
thousand 24 and a thousand are very
千24和一千非常
close to each other so two to the tenth
相互接近，从而两到第十
is roughly the same as 10 to the third
是大致相同的10到第三
so you take 64 and you think 60 so how
所以你拿64，你 认为 60所以如何
big is 2 to the 60 well that's 6 times
大是2到 60嗯，这是6倍
10 and therefore it's 6 times 3 it's
10，因此 它的6倍3是
like 10 to the 18th and then you add the
像10到18，然后你加入
4 to that that's 2 to the 4th and 16 so
4到这是2到第4和第16，
it's around 16 times 10 to the 18th
这是约16次，每次 10至18
fight so if you were to go off and look
打 所以如果你是走下车，并期待
online on Amazon for DRAM chips and try
在亚马逊网上的DRAM芯片，并尝试
to buy that much memory you'd find
买那么多的内存，你会发现
you're spending a lot of money more than
你花了很多钱超过
you I don't know the numbers but it
你不 知道的数字，但 它
would be a lot of memory money and so
将是一个很大的内存钱等
you basically can't do it nowadays tend
你基本上不能做到这一点现在倾向于
to the and so right now the machines
至所以现在 的 机器
limit you to actually only 47 bits worth
限制你实际上 只有47位等值
of address in the address space and so 2
在地址空间和地址，以便 2的
to the 47th again work that out that's
到 47 再工作了这一点这是
like 10 to the 12th times 256 times 10
像10到12倍256倍10
to the 12th so it's 256 terabytes and as
到12所以它的256兆兆字节和
you know you can buy a disk drive now
你知道你现在可以买一个磁盘驱动器
that has 8
有8
jeribai so it doesn't seem like that
jeribai所以它似乎并不像
much but if you tried to buy that much
很多，但如果你想 购买 那么多
DRAM again you'd have to have a pretty
DRAM再次你必须 有一个漂亮的
big credit-card limit and so even that's
大信用卡限制，所以即使这
a huge number and modern supercomputer
数量庞大的现代超级计算机
in situations actually will have almost
在实际情况下，将有近
that much memory but the point is that
这么大的内存，但问题是，
the hardware of today limits you to 47
今天的 硬件 限制到了 47
bits worth of address but that's not
位等值地址的，但是这不是
really a real limitation in terms of of
真正 的方面有真正的限制
actual machines and what will happen is
实际的机器 ，会发生什么是
is memory prices get cheaper and the
是内存的价格越来越便宜和
technology gets better they'll slowly
技术变得更好 ，他们会慢慢地
start adding as succeeding generations
开始添加的后代
of processors come along let you have
的处理器一起去让你拥有
bigger and bigger range of addresses so
越来越大范围的地址，以便
all that is to say that's why this
所有这就是说，这就是为什么这个
number shows up which is a seven
数显示 出来，其是七
followed by 11s I can tell I need to
其次是11S我可以告诉我需要
scribble some numbers you guys aren't
涂抹一些数字 你们都没有
just saying numbers in the air is not
只是说号码空气不
working here so let's try
在这里工作，所以让我们尝试
okay
好的
so remember I said before 264 is about
所以记得我 之前 说 264是关于
equal to 16 times 10 to the 18th - to
等于16倍10 到 18 -到
the 47th is 128 times 10 to the 12th so
第47次是128倍10 到 12，以便
it's 128 terabytes
这是128兆兆字节
so what's the number after a terabyte
有啥数 万亿字节 后
you know 10 to the 15th how many but yes
你知道10至15日有多少，但肯定
petabytes right
PB的右
and you know what 10v 18th is exha
你知道什么10V 18是 exha
so just as a reference a company like
所以只是作为参考这样的公司
Google roughly it's probably a total
谷歌大概 它可能是一个总
storage across the whole enterprises
在整个企业存储
measured in some small number of X bytes
在一些小 数目的X字节 测量
and it every day is getting several
它每天都越来越数
petabytes I don't know the numbers are
PB的我不知道的数字是
of course secret but maybe 10 petabytes
当然秘密，但也许10个千兆兆字节
or more per day of new data that it's
或每新数据的一天， 它更
ingesting into its system so these
摄取到它的系统，这些
numbers are pretty huge but not just
数字是相当巨大的，但不只是
totally off the charts do you know what
完全关闭的图表 ，你知道是什么
10 to the 21st is it's called a
10到21是它被称为
zettabyte with two t's
泽字节有两个 T的
and it's estimated if you add up all the
如果你 把所有 的它的估计
digital content in the world that gets
在获得世界数字内容
created everybody's cell phone camera
创建每个人的手机摄像头
every video taken by anyone anywhere all
任何人在任何地方采取的所有每个视频
year long is a couple of zettabytes a
一年之久 的一对夫妇一泽字节的
year so it'll be a while before we're
一年所以这将是一个虽然 我们之前
really having to deal with that kind of
真的有对付那种
memory so just just give you an idea so
内存所以才只给你一个想法 ， 所以
128 terabytes is the address limit on
128兆兆字节是在地址界限
these systems and so that's why you have
这些系统和所以这就是为什么你有
to have seven because you remember
以有七个 ，因为 你还记得
that's one two three and then there's F
这是一二三，然后有公司的 F
but there's 11 of them and this is one
但有他们的11，这是 一个
one one times 11 so that's 44 ones and
一个一个次11，这是44一和
this is three one and that's where you
这是三一，这就是你在哪里
get 47 and that's the address of the in
得到47，这就是在地址
Linux that's where they put the stack is
Linux的这就是他们把 堆栈
up at the very top of the address space
在高达地址 空间 的最顶端
and I should tell you this picture is
我应该告诉 你这幅画 是
not at all to scale it would be
不是所有 它 的规模 将是
impossible to draw this picture to scale
不可能得出这个画面缩放
for example it shows that the stack
例如，它示出了堆
starts way up at the top and remember
在顶部开始一路 上扬 ，并 记
stacks grow to smaller addresses when
堆栈增长到较小的地址时，
you're pushing and also we show the them
你推，也是我们展示他们
upside down just to make everything
倒挂只是使一切
confusing so the the stack starts there
混乱使堆栈从那里开始
and it grows towards lower addresses and
和它的增长向低地址 ，
on a typical system it will be limited
一个典型的系统上，将被限制
to 8 megabytes and you can tell that on
到8兆 ，你可以告诉大家，在
a Linux system at least with the the
Linux系统至少与该
limit command which used to be more
限制这曾经是多个命令
interesting that it was it is now
有趣的是，它现在是
because a lot of things are unlimited
因为很多 东西是无限的
but you see it says the stack size is
但是你看它说栈的大小
limited 8192 K bytes to kilobytes so
有限8192 千字节 为千字节 ，以便
it's 8 megabytes
这是8兆字节
and what that means is if you tried to
而这是什么意思是，如果你想
access any memory via the stack pointer
经由栈指针访问任意存储
that was outside of the range of this 8
这是 这 8 的范围之外
megabyte range you'd get a segmentation
兆字节的范围内，你会得到一个分割
fault and then down at the lower address
故障 再往下 在低位地址
is what comes in of what gets put into
是什么进来什么被投入
your program are the parts of the code
你的程序是代码的部分
that that come out of the executable
这是前来 可执行 的出
file and so there's a section and we'll
档案等有一个 部分，我们会
talk more when we talk about linking
聊得更多，当我们 谈论链接
actually about the way out of the memory
其实关于出路内存
and the different regions of it but for
和 它但对于不同地区
some obscure reason they they call where
他们称，他们那里的一些模糊的原因
the code is sitting the executable
该代码是坐在可执行
program the text segment I don't know
程序文本段 ，我不知道
why that's true but it's the way it is
为什么这是真的，但它的事情是这样的
nets across many machines and then the
多 台机器 ，然后将 网
data is first of all there'll be a
数据首先是那里将是一个
section for the data that's allocated it
对于已分配其数据段
the program begins so any global
节目开始，因此任何全球
variables that you've declared will be
你已经声明的变量会
in that section and then the heat is the
在该部分中，然后将热是
part of memory that is X is allocated
内存部分是 X分配
via call to malloc or one of its related
通过调用函数malloc或与其相关的一个
functions and so that varies dynamically
功能和，使得动态地改变
as the program runs it starts off with a
在程序运行时就开始了与 一
very small allocation and every time you
非常小的 分配，你每一次
call malloc
调用malloc
if you're not freeing memory and so your
如果你不释放内存等你
memory requirements keep growing it will
内存需求保持增长它会
crease keep up moving up larger and
折痕跟上连升更大，
larger addresses and then somewhere in
更大的地址，然后在某处
the code - and this can vary by system
代码 -并且这可以通过改变系统
is the code that gets brought in that
是 获取带来的代码
represents the library functions things
代表库函数的东西
like pretty and malloc itself our own
喜欢漂亮的malloc本身我们自己
library code they're stored off on disk
库代码他们在磁盘上存储关闭
and they get brought in they get linked
他们得到带来了他们获取链接
into your program when it first starts
到你的程序第一次启动时，它
executing by a process known as dynamic
通过被 称为动态 处理执行
linking which we'll talk about later in
联，我们将在后面 讨论
the course - with the linking and what
课程 -与链接什么
you'll find in general is that
你会发现在一般的是，
allocations will tend to be either at
分配将趋于无论是在
these very low addresses or these very
这些非常低的地址或这些非常
high addresses
高地址
as your program is running so just as an
为你的程序作为一个如此只是运行
example here is some code that it's only
这里的例子是一些 代码，这只是
value is to show you different where
价值是向您展示 不同的地方
things get located and so you'll see I
事情变得位于所以你会看到我
allocated some a fairly large arrays
分配一些相当大的数组
here this one is there all cares but
这里这个是有一切烦恼 ，但
this is 2 to the 24th so 16 a mega byte
这是2到第24次，以便16兆字节
array and this one is 2 to the 31st so
阵列和这个人是2到第31次，从而
it's 2 gigabytes worth of array I found
这是2千兆字节数组值得我找到了
that if I tried to allocate larger ones
如果我试图分配较大的
the program wouldn't run and I also do
该程序将无法运行，我也做
some here's just a sort of global
一些在这里只是一种全球
variable and here's a function and then
变量，这里是一个函数，然后
there's a single function here with some
这里有一个单一的功能与一些
local variable and that will be
局部变量， 这将是
allocated somewhere on the stack and
在栈上分配的地方和
then there's several calls to milk some
再 有就是多次 打电话给一些奶
of which are for some very small chunks
这些都是一些非常小的块
of memory and similarly where for some
的存储器并且类似地，其中一些
very large chunks of memory and so we
记忆，所以我们非常大的块
can run this program and see what
可以运行这个程序， 看看有什么
addresses pop out of it and what you'll
地址蹦出 它， 你会 是什么
see is the stack this local variable is
看到 的是堆栈这个局部变量
somewhere up with an address in the
了在地址某处
range of the stack and you see the 7 and
堆栈的范围内，您将看到7
a couple FS and then it goes to
一对夫妇的FS，然后它去
something else and you'll see also
别的东西，你还可以看到
interestingly enough that the codec and
有趣的是，该 编解码器 和
then looking down at the bottom of this
然后低头看着 这个 底部
yellow color is things get relegated to
黄色的事情被 降级
the text segment the main function and
文段的主要功能和
this function I called I declared called
这个功能我打电话给我叫宣
useless and then the predefined arrays
无用然后将预定义的阵列
that were in other words globally
那 名换句话说全球
declared not declared by malloc they're
宣布不malloc的他们宣布
declared as part of the program itself
声明为程序本身的一部分
are down here in this data section and
在这里倒在这个数据部分 ，
because it's a very large array the huge
因为它是一个非常大阵的巨大
array you actually get some fairly large
数组你实际上得到一些相当大的
addresses and then interestingly enough
地址，并十分有趣
or I don't know why it's interesting but
或者我不知道为什么它是有趣的，但
for one reason or another it happens
对于某种 原因 它发生
that the smaller chunks of memory
该存储器的更小的块
allocations are down here at addresses
分配是到这里的地址
that are actually just a little bit
这 其实只是一点点
above the the pink section right and
上面的粉红色部分和右
similarly the really big chunks of
类似的真正的大大块
memory allocated are way up here near
分配内存的方式在这里附近
the the stack limit and they and so
该堆栈限制，他们等
they're there and in general what's
他们在那里和一般的有什么
happening is if I were to try and
发生的事情是，如果我就是要尝试 和
reference a memory address in this empty
在这个空引用的存储器地址
range I'd get a segmentation fault it's
范围内我会得到一个分段错误 是
a valid address in terms of its bit of
在其位方面的有效地址
properties but it hasn't actually been
性能，但它 实际上并没有
set up and allocated by the memory the
建立和分配由内存
virtual memory allocator so at any given
虚拟内存分配器所以在任何 给定
time the valid addresses are just those
时间的有效地址， 只是那些
in the lower portion or the upper
在下部或上部
portion of his address ranges and the
他的 地址范围和的部分
middle is sort of no-man's land and then
中间是那种没有人的土地，然后
what happens is you keep allocating more
发生的事情是 你 保持分配更多
with malloc and it will push the limits
使用malloc，它会挑战极限
of what's addressable in toward it and
什么是可寻址的对着它
in principle if you ever got too much of
原则上，如果你曾经有 太多的
a memory request if these two would hit
如果这两个会打一个内存请求
each other and if you and melech would
对方如果你米勒 会
return zero at that point but it's
在这一点上返回零，但它
highly unlikely given that you have 128
高度 不太可能， 因为你有128
terabytes of memory address range here
内存地址范围太字节这里
so that's just and you've probably seen
所以这只是你可能见过
this when you're running you're looking
这个当你运行你正在寻找
at disassembled code with gdb you're
在使用gdb反汇编代码你
seeing some addresses that are way up
看到一些地址是一路上扬
here with the seven and some episodes or
这里有七个和一些情节或
stack addresses and you see these fours
堆栈地址， 你看到这些四肢
you know a lot of zeros and some fours
你知道很多 零和一些四肢 的
those tend to be where the code is going
这些往往是其中的代码是 怎么回事
to question
质疑
so why doesn't the heat proceed in one
所以为什么不热继续在一个
direction I actually don't know I'll
方向其实我 不知道我会
just observe that it was had a strategy
只是观察， 它是有一个战略
of putting big things here in small
这里把 大事小
things here and it probably uses
这里的东西， 它可能使用
different slightly different management
不同略有不同的管理
strategies for those two
对于 那些 两种 策略
okay so that but I think you'll find
还好使，但我认为你会 发现
that kind of useful to have some sense
那种非常有用 的一些感觉
when you're looking at when you're
当你看到的时候你在
running gdb it helps to just have some
运行GDB它有助于只是有一些
idea of what's going on when you're
这是怎么回事，当你在的想法
looking at these different addresses
看着这些 不同的地址
okay now let's talk about buffer
现在没事了，让我们来谈谈 缓冲
overflow and we'll start this you
溢出，我们将开始这个你
remember on the very first class and I
记得非常一流 的，我
think we might have reviewed this part
想我们可能 已对部分
way along we showed this example of some
沿着路我们发现 了一些 这个例子
programs where if you do an
在那里，如果你做一个节目
out-of-bounds reference and write a
外的边界 基准，写
value that's out of bounds in particular
值的出特别界
I only have a array of two elements here
我只有两个元素的数组这里
but this function will take an arbitrary
不过这个功能需要任意
value of I and assign some magic number
我的价值和分配一些神奇的数字
to omotte i of the array and it has the
到omotte i中的阵列的并且它具有
possibility of and we saw that when you
我们的可能性， 看到 你 的时候
do that if I get too big it will first
这样做，如果我得到过大，会先
corrupt the double that stored as part
腐败是存储部分双
of the struct and then when it gets
该结构的， 然后当它 得到
bigger it seems to not have any effect
大似乎没有 任何效果
until it gets too big and then you start
直到它变得太大， 然后你开始
corrupting memory so the basic point is
腐败存储器所以基本点是
that it's very easy in a program of C
它很容易在 C 程序
program in particular to a reference
方案特别涉及一种参考
memory that's not part of the sort of
内存不是那种的一部分
intent of the program and this can
该计划的目的，这可以
happen in programs that aren't properly
发生在节目 中不正确
written that and it becomes a security
撰文 指出 ， 和它成为一个安全
vulnerability if there's some way for an
漏洞 ，如果有一些 方法为
outsider to overflow a buffer for
局外人溢出了缓冲器
example if there is some way for an
例如，如果有某种方式为
outsider to give a larger value of I and
外人给我更大的价值 ，
ask that that value be stored there it
问该值 存储在那里 它
could crash the program and so in
能使整个程序崩溃，因此在
general when you write in code you try
一般来说，当你在代码编写你尝试
to think about you know can I trust this
想想你知道我可以信任这个
value is this a value that's been
值是这个是一直值
computed by my program and I'm sure that
我的计划计算，我敢肯定，
it's within bounds or is it something
它的范围内或者是它的东西
that
那
so come from an external source and
所以来自外部 源 和
there's potentially at risk of being a
那里的是一个危险的潜在
vulnerability so and so in particular
漏洞某某特别
there's a lot a huge class of errors
有很多 巨大的错误类
that have to do with overflowing buffers
具有与 缓冲器 溢出做
where where they're trying to store a
哪里哪里，他们正试图存储
string of some type that's been read
某种类型的字符串已经读过
from a message and without knowing in
从消息和 在 不知道
advance how big that string is it's
推进它有多大这个字符串是很
possible that it will be too big for the
可能，这将是太大了
buffer that's been allocated and so one
缓冲区一个已经 分配 等一个
of the culprits is there's a whole class
元凶是有一个全班
of of library functions that let you
的库函数，让 你
store something a string somewhere
存储的东西串的地方
without any kind of bounds checking even
没有任何一种界限，甚至检查
being possible so the sort of worst one
是可能因此是 最糟糕 的 一个
is one called get F and the purpose of
一个叫得到 F和目的
get S is normally it's used to read a
让小号通常它被用来 读取
string from an input from a terminal
从一个终端的输入串
input something that somebody's typed
输入的东西，有人在打字
into a terminal and so what it's doing
到 终端，因此它在做什么
is it's scanning this input string and
是它的扫描 这个输入字符串和
looking for a character that represents
寻找代表一个字符
the end of the line which we write in of
该行的 末尾 ，我们在写
CEA's is backslash n and it has the
CEA的是反斜杠n 和它有
character code in hex of zero a and so
在零 等 十六进制字符代码
get F this is sort of an approximate
得到F该 是 有点近似的
version of what the code forgetteth
什么代码forgetteth版本
looks like that and it as an argument
看起来像它作为参数
it's just given a destination of where
它只是给出其中目的地
to store the result and all it does is
存储 结果，它 是 所有
it reads one character at a time looks
它一次长相读取一个字符
for an into file meaning that the input
对于到文件的意思是输入
stream is closed or an end-of-line
流被关闭或结束线
but as long as it until it sees that it
但只要它，直到它发现它
just keeps adding more things to the end
只是不断 添加更多的东西到最后
of this buffer and so typically
此缓冲液中，因此通常
when somebody calls get us they'll pass
当有人打电话让我们，他们会通过
it a pointer to some buffer that they've
它的指针一定的缓冲，他们已经
allocated but the function and it will
但分配功能，它会
just get us we'll just fill that buffer
只是让我们 ，我们将只需填写该 缓冲区
up but it can potentially just keep
了，但它可能只是不停
going there is nothing in the function
去没有什么作用
there's not even an argument to the
甚至还有没有参数传递给
function that tells the function when
函数， 告诉功能时
when it has to stop when it's reached
当它停止时，它达到
the limit of it so it was written that
它的上限，从而使其被写 了
actually get at is if you try to compile
实际上得到的是，如果你尝试 编译
code would get us it will flash up a big
代码将让我们将闪了一大
warning that says this is really an
警告说，这是一个真正的
unsafe function you probably shouldn't
不安全的功能，你可能不应该
even be using it because it it has it
甚至可以使用它，因为它有 它
was written in an era in the 1970s when
写在一个时代在20世纪70年代时，
the early UNIX distributions were coming
早期 UNIX分布，未来
out where people just weren't worried
出人们只是不担心
about security vulnerabilities and they
有关安全漏洞和他们
just assumed that if you allocated a big
只是假设， 如果你分配一个大
enough buffer that there's no reason why
足够的缓冲区，有没有理由
a string should be bigger than what
字符串应大于什么
you've allocated and that's actually
你已经分配，这就是实际
true with other functions like stir copy
真正与 像搅 复制 等 功能
you recall stir copy has two arguments
你还记得 搅拌副本有两个 参数
excuse me a destination and a source and
原谅我的目的地和源和
its purpose is to copy the string at the
其目的是字符串 的 复制
source into the destination and the way
源到 目标和方式
it determines the end of the string and
它确定字符串的末尾和
the source is when it hits a null
源是当它击中空
character that just keeps copying one by
字符只是 不断复制一个
one wall until it hits it but it has no
一面墙上，直到它击中它，但它没有
way of knowing there's nothing no
办法知道有没有什么
information there about how much how big
多少信息有多大
is the buffer allocated at the
在缓冲的分配
destination and so it can easily overrun
目的地，因此它很容易 溢出
that a similar one called stir cat which
一个类似的一个叫猫轰动其中
is used to concatenate two strings and
用来连接 两个字符串
copy them to another destination and the
将它们复制到另一个目的地和
scanf function of also have possible in
也有可能在 scanf 函数
the format string you can give the
格式字符串可以 给
percent F directive to the format string
％的 ˚F 指令格式字符串
which says read in a string and store it
它说读取一个字符串，并将其存储
someplace
某个地方
and it doesn't say how long the string
并且它没有说多久字符串
is limited to be and it doesn't say how
被限制为，并没有 说如何
much memory is available at the
多少内存可用在
destination so again it can easily just
目的地，又可以 很容易只
write over that a buffer so these are
写了一个 缓冲器，这些都是
real vulnerabilities and we will talk in
真正的漏洞， 我们就会讨论
a minute a little later about how you as
一分钟 待会儿你如何 作为
a programmer can be a little smarter
程序员可以 聪明 一点
than this but in their suit of raw form
比这个，但在他们的原始形式的诉讼
as presented they have this
所呈现他们有这样的
vulnerability to them so let's look at
漏洞给他们，让我们来看看
an example of what this can what can
什么这样的例子可以什么都可以
happen there so imagine for example we
碰巧有这么想象， 例如 ，我们
want a to implement echo function so an
想要实现回声功能，所以一
echo function is one that you just type
回声功能是一个你 只需要输入
something in and it prints it back out
东西和它打印回来了
it's very uninteresting function except
这是除了很无趣功能
it's very useful to demonstrate things
它展示的东西非常有用
so the idea is it has this little buffer
这样的想法是有这个小缓冲区
it's only enough to hold four characters
它只够容纳四个字符
it caused geta to read a string from the
它 造成木屐 来读取一个字符串
input and then it calls put s which
输入，然后调用放 S的
simply writes back out the output and
简单地写回了输出和
and so let me just download this not
所以让我 下载这个不
very interesting function
非常有趣的功能
so I call it here buff demo - NST mean
所以我在这里 把 它 的buff演示- NST意思
it has no stack protector and we'll see
它 没有堆栈保护 ，我们会看到
in a minute what its deck protectors but
在一分钟内什么的甲板保护者，但
you see if you type a reasonably smoke
你看，如果你键入一个合理的抽烟
strong small string very rare it can
强大的小弦非常罕见的 它可以
handle more than four actually as
处理四个以上的居然
written it can't handle more than three
写它不能处理超过三个
right because there should be room for
正确的，因为应该有余地
the null character - on terminator so it
空字符-在终结所以
turns out with this particular one if I
原来，这个特殊的，如果我
type in a string of 24 characters it'll
键入24个字符的字符串， 它会
be okay
没关系
but if I type in a string of 24
但如果我在 24 String类型
characters it will hit a segmentation
字符将创下分割
fault
故障
so where do those numbers 23 and 24 come
所以在哪里这些数字23和24来
in well that's something we can learn by
在好这件事情，我们可以 通过 学习
looking at the assembly code
看汇编代码
so here's and we'll go through the code
所以这里的，我们将通过代码
so first of all this is the code for
所以首先这是代码
echo then and you see the echo calls get
回声，然后你看到的回声调用get
s and it calls put it and here's the
S和它要求把它和这里的
part of the code where you can tell how
部分的代码，你可以告诉如何
much memory got allocated for the buffer
多少内存得到分配的缓冲区
and x18 is what in decimal X 24 right
和X18就是十进制X 24 右
and you just saw that the thing actually
你刚才看到 实际的东西
seg faults with a input string of 24 so
SEG故障与24一个输入字符串，所以
we'll see that in a minute
我们会看到， 在一分钟内
but anyways you can see here that it's
但不管怎么说，你可以在这里看到它
allocating on the stack a region of 24
在堆栈上分配的24的区域
bytes and it's copying that into RDI
字节，它复制到这RDI
which is of course the argument
这当然是参数
forgetteth so get us is being called
forgetteth所以得到我们被称为
with a pointer to a buffer of size 24
的指针的大小24 的 缓冲
maximum 24 even though you saw the
最大24 即使你看到了
original declaration was just four for
原申报只有 4对
all and then it calls get s and then get
所有然后调用得到 秒，然后得到
us does it thing in just one last little
我们做这件事只是一个最后的 小
bit to keep in mind is we'll get back to
位牢记的是 ，我们会回来
them oh yes and remember echo that
他们哦， 是的，记住反响 ，
there's a function called call echo
有一个函数调用调用回声
which is the thing that calls echo and
这是调用回音的事情，
just to keep in mind this read is the
只是要记住这个读是
return address for call echo and that's
呼叫回波地址，这就是
going to be important
将是重要的
so what we see then is the memory layout
所以我们看到的又是什么内存布局
is the buff is normally big enough for
是的buff通常足够大 的
four characters there's a sort of 20
四个字符 有一种20
bytes of unused or wasted space here and
这里的闲置或浪费的空间字节
then the actual return address which is
那么实际的返回地址是
the return address for back to call echo
的返回地址回叫回声
is stored on the stack so when this
被存储在 栈上，所以当这个
program int begins running when echo
程序 INT开始运行时，回声
starts to run we'll find that this is
开始运行，我们会发现，这是
the value on the stack for the return
栈 为返回 的值
pointer and if we type in a string of up
指针，如果我们在一个 字符串的视 型
here of 23 characters you'll see that it
这里的23个字符 ，你会看到，它
uses up this entire buffer and remember
使用了 这个整个缓冲区和记忆
a string is terminated with a 0 0 but it
一个字符串终止于0 0，但它
still hasn't it's still within the
仍然没有它仍然是内
region that was allocated on the stack
这是在栈上分配的区域
for that so it just barely fits into the
对于这样它刚好 适合的
the stack and that's why we technically
堆栈，这就是为什么我们在技术上
we overflowed the buffer but we didn't
我们溢出的缓冲区，但我们没有
really cause any harm because there was
真正造成任何伤害，因为有
this extra space available and so that's
可用 ，所以这就是这个额外的空间
why I could type in that string of 23
为什么我能在23字符串类型
characters and and it worked fine but
字符，它工作得很好 ，但
now if I type in this is an example
现在如果我在这个类型是一个例子
showing
展示
I actually 25 characters so once I go
其实我 25个字符， 所以一旦我走
beyond the 23 characters plus the null
超过23个字符加空
character you'll see what I'm slowly
性格你就会明白我 慢慢地
starting to do is is corrupt the the the
开始做的是损坏了 的
byte representation of the return
返回的字节表示
address and so what happens for example
地址等什么， 例如发生
here is that rather than trying to
这里要说的是，而不是试图
return back to the where call echo was
返回到 哪里通话回声
supposed to where it was supposed to go
应该到它应该去
back to it goes back to some other part
回到它可以追溯到 其它部分
of your code that may or may not be a
你的代码 可能会或可能不会是一个
valid address or might not have anything
有效的地址或可能不会有什么
to do with the program you're trying to
做你想要的程序
run so this example shows it and if I
跑那么这个例子显示了它，如果我
typed in the 24
键入24
let's see before I got it to run like
让我们来看看我得到它 像 之前运行
this you know this thing depends on the
这一点，你知道这件事情依赖于
what happens how the code happens to get
会发生什么代码是如何发生的，以获取
compiled oh yeah so okay so actually you
编译哦，是这么好了，其实你
see here this first string I typed is
看到这里我输入这个第一个字符串
actually 24 characters long plus the
其实24个字符长加
null pointer so and we'll see why it
空指针所以，我们会看到为什么
didn't it should have crashed because we
没有它应该崩溃，因为我们
actually over I wrote the low order byte
其实 在我写 的低位字节
of the return address here we typed in
返回地址在这里我们键入
this is 25 characters and so that's the
这是25个字符，所以这是
one I just showed where it really
一个我刚才给它真正
whacked the two bytes of the return
疲惫不堪返回 的两个字节
address so here we actually did overflow
解决所以在这里，我们实际上做了溢出
the buffer and let's try and figure out
缓冲，让我们试着 找出
why that didn't harm the the program
为什么不存在损害程序
execution I see a question yes it could
执行我看到一个问题，是的， 它可能
have been various other things could
已经有多种其他的东西可以
have there's nothing it hit a
有没有什么它击中
segmentation fault because it probably
分段错误 ，因为它 可能
went to some weird part of the code and
到 了代码 的一些奇怪的一部分 ，
just started executing some random stuff
刚刚开始执行一些随机的东西
and it just got itself into trouble but
它刚刚得到自己变成 麻烦，但
that's the point is it's not predictable
这就是问题所在是它的不可预测的
exactly what will happen when you do
究竟会 发生 什么 ，当你做
this
这个
so this is that the example of what
所以这是的例子 是什么
actually happened the first time when I
当我实际发生的第一次
typed in a string that had 24 characters
键入在有24个字符的字符串
and so this null byte at the end
所以在最后这个空字节
actually corrupted the return address
实际损坏的返回地址
and so it was supposed to return back to
所以它应该回到返回
this address 400 6f6 and instead it will
这个地址400 6F6和相反，它会
return back to the address 400 600 which
返回到地址 400 600，
happens to be in some other weird
恰好是在其他一些怪异
function that's there and it just sort
功能的存在，它只是排序
of landed at some place here and it's
在一些地方 降落 在这里，它的
doing various things but somehow it
做各种事情 ，但不知何故，
didn't really didn't crash the program
没有真的没有程序崩溃
and that's one of the frustrating things
这就是的 令人沮丧的事情 一个
about this is that things can go wrong
这个是事情都可能出错
in a program and they don't always cause
在程序 中 ，他们并不总是引起
a crash and so often a bug that's
崩溃，并且经常错误这是
working there might be doing some weird
工作有可能会做一些奇怪的
stuff that you don't even know about so
的东西，你甚至不 知道这么
that's all a fine if it's just a way of
这是所有的罚款，如果它只是一个方式
crashing programs and I mean that's not
崩溃的程序，我的意思是这不是
great if it's controlling your pacemaker
伟大的，如果它控制你的心脏起搏器
or something like that but if it's just
或类似 的 东西 ，但如果它只是
a homework assignment it's like not a
家庭作业就好像不是一个
big deal so uh but what actually and
大不了所以 呵，但究竟和
this is sort of only happened since
这是那种只发生以来
attacking became a normal activity which
进攻成为一种正常的活动，其
has only been the last 30 years is that
至今只有近30 年来 的是，
it gives an opportunity for a hacker or
它提供了一个机会，让 黑客 或
a attacker to inject code into the
一个攻击者将代码注入的
program and execute it and that's what's
程序并执行它，那是什么
called a code injection attack and so
所谓的代码注入攻击等
the the general scheme of it is I have
它的总体方案 是我
this buffer that I can fill up with
该缓冲区 ，我可以填补
whatever bytes I want by feeding them to
无论字节我想他们喂养
get s or whatever function is doing this
获得S或任何功能，这样做
copying and what I can do then is set up
复制和我能做些什么，然后 设置
and pass to it some bytes of actually
并传递给它 的实际一些字节
that encode an executable a little bit
编码可执行一点点
of executable code you've seen an object
可执行代码，你见过一个对象
dump it's printing out these bytecode
转储它打印出这些 字节码
representations of instructions so
指令表示这样
imagine you said some of those byte
想象一下，你说其中一些字节
into your string you encoded them in the
为您的字符串你在编码它们
string that you pass to get us and then
您 传递字符串让我们再
you might have to add some more sort of
您可能 需要添加 更多的 排序
padding characters that characters whose
填充字符的字符，其
value doesn't matter in order to then
值不会为了之至然后
get a number back into the position
得到一个数字回到位置
where the return pointer is supposed to
在返回指针应该
be and so what's call that number B it's
是还等什么的调用号 B很
going to be an address one of these ones
将是一个地址，这些的人之一
with the you know that represents a
与你知道代表
stack location and that value B then is
堆位置和值 B然后是
the starting address of the buffer which
缓冲区的起始地址，其
happens to be where your exploit code
恰好是在您的攻击代码
remember this is just executable
记住这仅仅是可执行文件
instructions of were stored here so now
指令是如此，现在存放在这里
what will happen is when the program
会发生什么是程序
does its return here it was supposed to
没有它的回报在这里它应该
return back to wherever it got called
回到返回无论它得到了所谓的
from P
与P
this is a typo P calls Q not far so it's
这是 一个错字p拨打。q 没有到目前为止它的
supposed to return back to P and we're
本来要返回 P和 我们
and the address the return address was
和地址的返回地址是
stored here
存储在这里
but now I've overwritten that return
但现在我已经 被覆盖时返回
address with this buffer position so
用该缓冲液位置，从而解决
what will happen is the the program
会发生什么是程序
counter will happily jump to this spot
计数器会很乐意跳转到这个地方
and see start executing whatever it
看看开始执行不管它
encounters which are the instructions
遭遇它们是指令
that you've inserted and by that means
你已经插入并通过手段
then you can inject code into a machine
那么你可以将代码注入机器
potentially somewhere up in the Internet
潜在的地方了在 互联网
if you could set up a scheme like this
如果你能建立 这样 的方案
that would feed these bytes into that
这将养活这些字节成
machine and it would read it in with a
机 ，它会与阅读
function like get us and then it would
功能一样让我们，然后它会
try to do its return but it would start
尝试做它的回报，但它会启动
executing your code so that's the
执行你的代码， 所以 这是
classic code injection attack and in
经典代码注入攻击和
fact in this lab that you're going to
事实上，在这个实验中，你会
start it comes out at midnight called
它开始在 半夜 叫 出来
the attack lab because you're going to
攻击实验，因为你要
do this yourself for part of the lab and
该 实验室 的一部分，这样做你自己，
I think you'll find it pretty
我想你会很找到它
interesting so this used to be a huge
有趣所以这曾经是一个巨大的
problem on programs yet so when you're
上节目 又 那么当你的问题
trying to replace read I make sure that
试图取代阅读我要确保
your new submitted read overrides that
新提交的阅读将覆盖
exactly well that's part of the cover
也正是这就是盖的一部分
nets of being a hacker you have to make
被黑客 你 的网 必须做出
sure it's in the right spot
确保它在正确的 位置
but it's actually one of the easier
但 它实际上是比较容易的一个
parts because for example we do know you
部分因为比如说我们知道你
have to know the binary code to be able
必须知道的二进制代码， 能够
to do this or be able to guess so for
要做到这一点还是能 猜到这样的
example in that previous one I could
例如，在以前的一个 我可以
tell that it was allocating 24 bytes for
告诉它被分配24个字节
that buffer and so if I just made sure
该缓冲区，因此，如果我只是确信
that the length of my exploit code plus
我的长度攻击代码加
the padding is 24 bytes then right after
填充为24个字节，然后右后
that comes to the return address so
这涉及到的返回地址，以便
that's actually pretty easy to do there
这其实很 容易做到有
was
是
certainly how much memory programs uh no
当然多少内存的 程序呃没有
you have to have access you have to what
您有权访问 你有 什么
the reason why this works is it works if
为什么这个工作 的 原因 是它的工作原理，如果
you have enough knowledge about the
您有 足够 的 知识
operating system that's running at the
多数民众赞成在运行的操作系统
other end for example you know it's
另一端，例如，你知道这是
Linux you know that you can look at
Linux下，你知道，你可以看看
either what GCC tends to allocate for it
无论是什么GCC往往要分配给它
you somehow have access to information
你会莫名其妙地获得 信息
about the code itself lets you do this
有关代码本身可以让你做到 这一点
so anyways this used to be a huge
所以反正这里曾经是一个巨大的
problem and it started way back in 1988
问题并开始，早 在1988年
the first internet attack was called the
第一网络攻击被称为
Morris worm and it at the time the
Morris蠕虫病毒，它在当时
internet was not a very big place and it
互联网是 不是一个非常 大的地方 ，它
basically brought down a huge fraction
基本上放倒了巨大的分数
of the machines that were on the
这是对 机器
internet at the time
互联网在当时
interestingly enough CMU did not fall
有趣的是CMU 不降
victim to this attack because we'd
受害者受到这种攻击，因为我们会
patched already the vulnerabilities that
修补已经是漏洞
this particular program exploited and
这个特定的程序开发和
that was the cause that the software
这是原因，该软件
engineering Institute runs an
工程学院的运行
organization called cert the computer
组织称为证书的计算机
emergency response team and that team
应急队伍和 团队
was set up in response to this attack
在 回应 设立这种攻击
the Morris worm attack will also see an
Morris蠕虫病毒的攻击 也将看到一个
interesting example between two
两者之间的有趣的例子
companies in in messaging services and
公司在信息服务和
many others it's been the sort of
许多人它已经的那种
standard attack mechanism for many years
标准的攻击机制多年
and fortunately nowadays there's a few
幸运的是现在有几个
things that make the attacking of less
的事情，使较少的攻击
likely to be successful and so it's not
可能是成功的，所以它不是
as huge a problem as it used to be but
因为它曾经是一个巨大的问题，但
still it's a source of many
它仍然是许多的来源
vulnerabilities in programs so let's see
在程序漏洞， 让我们看看
I won't talk too much about this but it
我不会过多谈论 这一点，但它
used to be
以前是
in the original implementation of
在原 执行
there's a command that most systems have
还有，大多数系统都有一个命令
now disabled that you could finger you
现在禁用，你可以用手指你
could across the information about
横跨有关信息能
somebody in some remote location it
有人在一些偏远的 位置，它
would send a message to that location
将消息发送到该位置
and then it would reply back and it used
然后它会在回信中，它使用
get assets on the actual original
得到实际的原始 资产
implementation called get s to read the
实施名为get s 到 读
input string from that was being sent to
从输入字符串被发送到
it
它
and then there is an interesting one you
然后有一个有趣的 你
guys don't remember messaging instant
男人不记得通讯即时
messaging but before it used to be that
消息，但之前曾经是
people would talk to each other on their
人们 会 互相 交谈 他们的
computers by sending messages sort of
通过发送某种 信息的计算机
like you send text messages today but
就像你今天发短信，但
there is an interesting thing that
还有一个有趣的事情，
there's a company still exist but it's a
还有的公司依然 存在，但 它是一个
shadow of its former self called AOL
它的前自已的阴影称为AOL
which ran the most popular Internet
跑最流行的互联网
services and had the most popular
服务和有最流行
instant messaging program and Microsoft
即时通讯程序和Microsoft
came out with its own client its own
推出了它自己的客户自己的
program that you could run on your
你可以在运行程序的
machine and communicate to other people
机 和交流给其他人
on this messaging system so the
此消息系统上，因此将
Microsoft code was running on your
微软的源代码上正在运行的
machine but it would use the servers
机器，但它会使用服务器
that were being run by AOL to manage
，正在通过 AOL 运行 管理
this messaging traffic and the funny
此消息流量和搞笑
story was over that the this Microsoft
故事结束了这个微软
program would work fine you can
程序会工作得很好 ，你可以
communicate with your friends who had
与您的朋友谁了 沟通
different messaging clients and it all
不同的消息客户端，这一切
seemed compatible but then suddenly the
似乎兼容，但随后突然
people that were running the Microsoft
人们都 在 运行 Microsoft
version of the software it wouldn't work
该软件的版本， 它是行不通的
and then Microsoft people figured out
然后微软人想通了
how to patch it and then it would work
如何修补它，然后它会工作
for a while and then it wouldn't work
一会儿 ，然后它不会工作
and the way what was happening was a o/l
和发生了什么事的方式是一个 Ø/升
was using a bug in its own code to be
使用中的错误在自己的代码是
able to determine who's basically peek
能够确定谁是基本上偷看
into the the machines on the client side
为在客户端的机器
and do a buffer overflow attack on your
并做了缓冲区溢出攻击 你的
code that were you running on your
代码是 你运行你的
machine and then basically peek around
机器，然后基本上围绕偷看
and see does this look like AOL coders
看看， 这看起来像AOL编码器
it's something or is it some foreign
它的东西， 或者是一些国外
code and so is basically able to use its
码等， 基本上能够使用其
own security weakness to figure out this
自身的安全漏洞，找出这个
information and that got disclosed by a
信息 和得到了由公开
sort of funny message from somebody who
排序从 别人滑稽的消息是谁
called himself filled buckin and it was
称自己充满buckin，这是
determined that
确定
this email originated from somewhere
该邮件来自某处
within Microsoft so anyways that the and
在微软内部，从而反正是，和
you can read more about it in the book
你可以阅读 更多关于 它的书
around the slide so fun stories so in
绕滑动如此有趣的故事所以在
general in the security world you're
一般在安全 的世界你
supposed to distinguish between the idea
本来的想法来区分
of a worm and a virus although people
蠕虫和病毒，虽然人
aren't very good at doing that
是不是 在这样做 非常好
so worm is a program that can run on its
这样的蠕虫是可以在运行程序的
own and propagate itself from one place
拥有并从一个地方传播自身
to the other replicated a virus is like
其他复制的病毒样
a biological virus it doesn't live on
生物病毒 并不住在
its own it works by attacking a program
其自身的工作原理，攻击 程序
and basically modifying that program's
基本上修改 程序
behavior so that can see the basic idea
行为，以便能够看到的基本概念
of buffer overflows and you'll see it
的缓冲区溢出，你会看到它
more first hand so let's look at
更多的第一手资料 ，以便让我们来看看
techniques that machines can use to
该机器可以使用技巧
avoid to make themselves less vulnerable
避免让自己不那么脆弱
to these attacks well first of all you
这些攻击 以及首先你
the application or the writer on the
该应用程序或 在作家
server side can write code that's more
服务器端可以编写代码，更
secure so for example what you're
确保因此，例如，你在做什么
supposed to do instead of get ass as use
应该做的， 而不是让 驴作为使用
a function called F get us an F getta
一个称F功能让我们 一个 F GETTA
has the property that it passes a
拥有它 传递一个 属性
parameter which is the maximum number of
参数，其是的最大 数量
bytes that the program should read and
字节程序应该读和
it's there's more bytes than that in the
它还有比这在更多的字节
input it will just truncate the input so
输入它只会截断输入，所以
on you're really supposed to use F get
对你真的应该使用 F取得
us and give a limit similarly stur copy
我们，给一个限制同样stur副本
there is a version of it called stern
有一种叫船尾版本
copy where you can give a limit and with
副本，你可以给一个极限值，并与
a scanf you're supposed to be careful
一个scanf函数你应该要小心
about using the percent s and there's
有关使用百分比S和有
even a terminology you can say percent
甚至一个术语，你可以说 百分之
give a number that the maximum length of
给一个数字的最大长度
the string it should read so these
它应该阅读等等这些字符串
various places you can protect your code
不同的地方，你可以保护你的代码
to make sure it won't overflow buffers
以 确保它不会溢出缓冲区
unfortunately and a lot of code has been
不幸的是，很多代码已经
you'd call it hardening it's been people
你把它硬化它已经人
have gone through it and it's a lot of
已经 通过它 走了 ，这是一个很大的
work because there's a lot of places in
工作，因为有一个 在很多地方
programs where you're copying strings
计划在那里你复制串
from one point
从一个点
to another and there are a lot of real
另一个有很多真正的
subtleties like when you're converting
细微之处，当你像转换
from Unicode to bytes and so forth that
从Unicode到字节等 那
you're going back and forth between
你来回之间
different character encodings but for
不同的字符编码但
the large part and these tools that the
在很大程度上和 这些工具 的
code developers have created to help
代码开发者已经创建了帮助
track down these bugs so it's become a
追踪这些bug，所以它成为了
little bit safer out there but there's
点点的安全在那里，但有
still vulnerabilities so then there's
仍然漏洞所以后来有
other parts where you just try to build
其他地方，你只尝试建立
in safeguards into the system that would
在保障进入系统，将
make it much harder to do a buffer
使它更难做一个缓冲
overflow exploit like I showed you and
溢出攻击像我向您 和
so one of them is called stack
所以他们中的一个被 称为栈
randomization or it goes by a more
随机或它的推移更
general term that's abbreviated aslr
多数民众赞成简称ASLR总称
which stands for address space layout
它代表的地址空间布局
randomization
随机
and the idea that is to make it so every
那 就是这个想法让它所以每
time a program run the addresses change
时间程序运行地址 变更
a little bit or a lot so that you can't
一点点还是很多，所以你不能
reliably know where things are going to
可靠地知道事情会
be in the code so imagine for example
在 代码 这样想象例如
the and the way it's implemented is
它的实施和方式是
before in the sort of run-up of your
之前在排序的运行你的
program when it first starts up but
程序时， 它首先启动，但
before your main routine gets called it
在你的主程序被调用时，
will just do allocation on the stack of
只会做的堆栈分配
some random number of bytes and storage
字节 和存储 的一些随机数
a fair amount like maybe a megabyte
相当数量的像，也许一兆字节
roughly of storage where the exact
的大致存储，其确切的
number is randomly chosen and what that
号码是随机选择和什么
means is that the the dress of the stack
手段是，堆叠的着装
of all the different positions of your
所有不同 位置的你
ear all the local storage on the stack
耳朵所有堆栈上 的本地 存储
will shift up and down from one run to
从一个运行转向向上和向下
another and we can actually see that in
另外，我们可以清楚地看到，在
this example I showed
这个例子我展示
so I have a program here it's not a very
所以我有一个程序， 在这里 它不是 一个非常
interesting program I'll show you except
有趣的节目，我会告诉你，除了
to demonstrate these ideas
证明这些想法
all it's doing is there's some code it's
所有它做的是有一些代码，它的
based on that one I already showed code
基于这样一个我已经表现出码
locate but this one there's a global
找到，但这个有一个全球
variable there's some functions there's
变量 有一些功能 有
something that gets allocated by malloc
这被通过的malloc分配的东西
and there's something that is a local
这里面的东西， 是一个本地
variable stored on the stack and so what
变量保存在栈 还 等什么 的
I'll do is show addresses that are
我会做的是，在展会地址
chosen the address of this variable then
选择这个变量的地址，然后
will be a stack address a local of a
将是一个堆栈地址的本地的
local variable global will be this one
局部变量全球将是这一个
that gets allocated globally the heap is
这被全球分配的堆
something allocated with malloc and then
一些使用malloc，然后分配
the this function useless will count as
在这个函数无用将算作
a code address and now when I run it
代码的地址，现在当我运行
you'll see from one run to another that
你会看到从一个运行到另一
if some of these stay the same and some
如果其中的一些保持不变，一些
of them change so in particular the
其中尤其 是 如此改变
global variable is the same 600 102 C
全局变量是相同的600 102℃
and the code is the same for double O 5
和代码是用于双O 5相同的
900 is the same every execution but
900是每一个 执行 相同的 ，但
you'll see this local variable it's on a
你会看到这个局部变量是在
stack address but you see that the lower
堆栈地址，但你看到更低
half dozen or so bikes are actually
半打左右的自行车实际上是
changing from one run to another 1 2 3 4
从一个运行转换到另一种1 2 3 4
5 so 5 bytes of it but 5 hex digits I'm
5，以5个字节， 但5个十六进制数字我
sorry so that's 2 to the 20th so roughly
抱歉，所以这是2到20大致如此
a megabyte of variation is going on in
变化一兆字节是 怎么回事
stack addresses there and similarly
堆栈地址有， 同样
you'll see that the heap addresses are
你会看到堆地址
also varying from one to another from
还从一个 从改变到另一个
one execution to the other so malloc has
一个执行到另一个这样的malloc具有
built into it some amount of randomness
内置到它 的随机性 一定量
to in its allocation so what why setec
在其分配等什么 ，为什么SETEC
you know what's the purpose of that well
你知道那是什么 井 的目的
as I told you this code injection
我告诉你，这个代码注入
vulnerability relies on the fact that
脆弱性依赖于一个事实， 即
you can you can load up this buffer with
您可以您可以加载了这个缓冲带
some executable code
一些可执行代码
but somehow you have to know how to get
但不知为何，你必须 知道如何获得
to the start of that code and this is
该代码的 开始 ，这是
relying the attack is relying on the
依托攻击是依靠
fact that it can somehow predict what
事实上，它可以以某种方式预测什么
the this address of the buffer is and so
缓冲区的这个地址等
that it can store it in the right part
它可以将其存储在右部
of the string put it encoded in the
字符串的把它放在编码
right part of the string so it will show
字符串的右边部分， 因此会显示
up where the return pointer is supposed
了在返回指针应该
to be and and have it jumped to that
是和并 使其 跃升到
location but now with this randomization
的位置，但现在有了这个随机
this number is varying by quite a bit
这个数字是相当多的不同
sort of million over a range of a
排序万元以上的范围的
million or so values so there's no way
万个左右的值，所以没有办法
in advance even if I have an exact copy
提前即使我有完全相同的副本
of the code not even had access to the
代码 甚至没有给接入
system itself and could run it I can't
系统本身可以运行它，我不能
predict from one run to the next where
从一个运行预测到下一个地方
it's going to be so that gives it sort
它会是这样，给 它排序
of fort this particular attack to to
堡这个特殊 的攻击，以
make it using this randomization
使用这张随机它
another idea that fairly straightforward
另一个想法相当简单
but it took a long time for the hardware
但它花了很长时间 的硬件
people to implement this is well why why
人们去实现，这是很好为什么为什么
is there supposed to be code on the
在那里应该是代码的
stack in the first place isn't the code
堆叠在第一位置是不是 代码
supposed to be located down in the text
应该是位于倒在文本
segment where it can be sued especially
细分市场，它可以被起诉尤其
identified as being executable so in the
确定为可执行所以在
original x86 there's a one bit flag for
原来的x86有一个为一个一位标志，
each region of memory saying is it
内存 句话 的每一个区域是它
actually - one bit flags one is can this
其实-一个位标志 之一是可以这样
be written to so that you can prevent
写入，这样就可以防止
overwrite so things like string
覆盖所以像串
constants and so and then the other is
常数等，然后将 另 一种是
am I can I read it and read means access
我是我可以阅读和阅读方式访问
those bytes and it was interpreted that
这些 字节，它被解释为
readable and executable were the same
可读和可执行是相同
thing I can read it I can execute it and
事我可以读它， 我可以执行它，
that was the rule in a sort of last 10
那是在一个排序的最后10规则
years or so starting first with AMD and
年左右 ，与AMD 和 启动第一
then Intel have added a third bit that
那么英特尔已经增加了第三位的是
says is this executable or not similarly
说的是这不是可执行类似
to the permissions you have on a file on
在权限你有一个文件
UNIX is it readable writable executable
UNIX是它可写可读可执行
those are three separate permission bits
这些三个单独的许可位
that are alone so by simply marking the
是单独所以通过简单的标记的
stack is not executable it'll also port
堆栈是不是可执行程序，它还会端口
this particular attack because I have to
这种特殊的攻击，因为我有
be able to execute these bytes as I've
可以，因为我已经执行这些字节
injected into the system
注入系统
and then there's the final idea which is
再有就是最终的想法是
actually fairly effective - which they
实际上是相当有效的 -他们
call a canary that they built into the
叫他们建成了一个金丝雀
stack and some of you actually
栈和你们中的一些实际
encountered this code already and
已经遇到了这个代码 和
looking at your bombs because we've been
看着你的炸弹，因为我们已经
getting some questions about it so let
得到 关于它 的一些问题， 所以让
me just give you an example here
我只是给你 在这里 的 例子
and this one's called buff demo - SP
而这一次的所谓的buff演示- SP
because it's been compiled with what
因为它被编译什么
they call stack protector and this one
他们调用堆栈保护这一个
now it's the same code as before it's
现在是相同的代码之前，它是
just compiled a little bit differently
刚刚编译略有不同
what you'll find is I can give a string
你会 发现，我可以给一个字符串
of length 8 and not have a problem but
长度为8，而不是有一个问题，但
if I now have 9 characters it will dump
如果我现在有9个字符将倾倒
out with this very strange exit error
出这个很奇怪退出错误
message that is an indication that it
消息，是它的指示
detected a attempt to smash the stack so
检测到的尝试破坏堆栈所以
buffer overflow is sometimes called
缓冲区溢出有时也被称为
stack smashing so it detected somehow
栈砸所以它以某种方式检测到
that even though I my code was still the
即使我在我的代码仍然是
same old crappy code from before of a
从一个前老蹩脚的代码
very small buffer allocation and no
很小的缓冲区分配和无
protection somehow the the system
保护莫名其妙的系统
protected me from myself and that's a
从我自己的保护我，这是一个
via a relatively simple trick that's
通过相对简单的窍门对于
fairly clever though what they call step
相当聪明的，虽然他们称之为一步
canary so that the term canary comes
金丝雀，这样的术语来金丝雀
back from a back in the coal mining days
从煤炭开采天背背
of old before they had very good ways of
老之前， 他们有很好的途径
measuring things they take a bird down
测量的东西，他们采取 了下来鸟
with them in a cage and a canary is a
与他们关在笼子里和金丝雀是一种
property that's very susceptible to
属性，它是非常容易
dying if there's nothing if there's
如果死亡没有什么，如果有
methane gas present so these miners
本甲烷气体所以，这些矿工
would be down there working and they'd
是那里 工作， 他们会
see their bird keel over and say oh we
看到自己的鸟龙骨过来，说哦，我们
got a problem here what get out fast so
有一个问题在这里得到什么了 这么 快
that's why they call it a canary in a
这就是为什么他们称之为的金丝雀
coal mine sometimes some kind of warning
煤矿有时某种警告
signal that that something's not not
发出信号的东西不是不
right here and in general we see a GCC
这里和一般我们看到了GCC
if you invoke it with a stack protector
如果你有一个堆栈保护调用它
nowadays that's the default so even
时下是默认 所以即使
without you saying anything
没有你说什么
this code will get built into it and so
这个代码将获得内置到它，所以
let's look at what that canary code
让我们来看看这是什么金丝雀代码
looks like and how it does its thing
貌似和 它是 如何 做的事情
it's really pretty clever as I said and
这是 因为我说的真的很漂亮聪明
some of you have already observed this
你们当中有些人已经观察到了这种
strange kind of memory reference in a
怪样的内存引用
register reference in the code and your
注册代码和参考
BOM labs because it it was compiled with
BOM的实验室，因为 它与编译
this deck protecting enabled because
这种限制对甲板启用，因为
that's the default and so in particular
这是默认的 ，因此特别
what this code shows is it allocating as
这 是什么 代码显示了它是 作为分配
before 24 bytes on the stack but now
之前在堆栈上的24个字节，但现在
it's getting some number and we'll talk
它得到一些号码，我们将讨论
in a second what that means and storing
在第二个是什么意思和存储
it at position 8 offset from the stack
它在位置8处从堆栈 偏移
pointer and then the rest of the code
指针，然后 将代码 的其余部分
and then it zeros it out that's not to
然后归零出来，这 并不是
worry and then it looks like the your
担心然后它看起来像你的
previous code that it's passing a
上面的代码，它的传递
pointer to the stack the top of the
指针堆栈的 顶部
stack as the argument to get us and get
堆栈的说法让我们，让
us it gets called and then put s gets
我们它被调用，然后把就会越来越
called but now there's some more code
所谓的，但现在有一些更多的代码
here that is it involves this
这里是它涉及到 这
strange-looking register and then
奇怪的注册，然后
there's some kind of test and then if
有一些类型的测试，然后如果
that tests fail it will call this a code
该测试失败，将调用此代码
that you just saw printed out this error
你 刚才看到打印出来这个错误
message so let's see what that all means
消息让我们看看这 一切手段
what that means is that it offset 8 from
这是什么意思是，它从偏移8
the stack pointer it's putting in 8
它投入8堆栈指针
bytes of value that it's retrieving from
的价值，它的检索 从 字节
a special register so FS is a reference
专用寄存器所以FS是一个参考
to a type of register that was created
到已创建的类型寄存器的
for the original 8086 and is now
对于最初的8086和现在
completely obsolete but it's still there
完全过时，但它仍然存在
for backward compatibility mode but what
为了向后 兼容模式 ，但什么
it is is and I actually I looked and
它是，我实际上我 看着和
I've never fully been able to find the
我从来没有完全能够找到
documentation on it it's able to read
它的文档是能够读取
from a part of memory a set of values
从存储器的 设置值的 一部分
that you can't otherwise get to
你 不能以其他方式得到
and so that the Khmer canary is getting
所以高棉 金丝雀越来越
a somehow its grabbing eight bytes from
一个莫名其妙的抓八个字节
somewhere storing it as this canary
地方把它作为这个金丝雀
value and then if you give like a seven
值，然后如果你给像七
character input so you would affect the
字符输入，所以你会影响到
canary and so what happens when it
金丝雀等会发生什么时
returns from the two calls from get us
从两个调用返回的让我们
and put us before it exits what it's
并把我们退出就是它的前
trying to detect is has anything as this
尝试检测是有什么，因为这
buffer somehow overflowed and
缓冲区溢出莫名其妙和
potentially at risk of of corrupting
在潜在的腐败风险
some other part of the stack so
堆栈的一些其他部件以便
basically what it does is it retrieves
基本上它是它检索
back from the stack what is the current
从堆栈后面什么是当前
value of this canary and it's comparing
该金丝雀 的价值和它的比较
it to what it should be by retrieving
它应该是 通过检索什么
that back from this special region and
从这个 特殊的区域是背部和
if they're equal it says fine but if
如果他们是平等的 ，它说正常，但如果
they're not equal it's detecting that
他们不是等于它的检测
it's got corrupted so just like the
它被 损坏 所以就像
canary in the coalmine
金丝雀在 煤矿
if these bytes get corrupted in any form
如果这些字节被损坏，以任何形式
it's an indication that something went
这是一个迹象表明，出事
wrong now that example shows that if I
错了，现在例子表明，如果我
have a seven character string then I'm
有七个字符串那么我
not going to corrupt the canary but you
不会破坏金丝雀但 你
notice I just got away with an eight
请注意我 只是一个八逃走了
character string so let me just see
字符串，所以让我只看到
what's going on here
什么是怎么回事
I won a character string right oh please
我赢得了一个 字符串的权利哦，请
lately
最近
so I have to look I don't have the code
所以我要看看我没有代码
in front of me so I have to look at
在我面前让我不得不看
so anyways here's where it's subtracting
所以反正这里的地方它的减
24 from the stack pointer and then the
24 从 堆栈指针 ，然后将
next instruction is retrieving this
下一条指令检索 该
canary values so let's figure out what
金丝雀值， 所以让我们弄清楚什么
the canary is right now we are at
金丝雀是正确的，现在我们正处于
72f so we're at the first instruction
72F所以我们在第一条指令
here let's do another step
在这里让我们做另一步
so this is the canary and it you'll see
所以这是一只金丝雀，还有 它，你会看到
actually when from 100 others get a
实际上，当100人获得
different value of it so it's perfectly
它不同的值 ，因此这是 完全
put in there in a way that it's
摆在那里的方式， 它是
unpredictable the one thing you'll
不可预测 的一件事，你会
notice is that the low order byte is
通知是低位字节
zeroes and so apparently they knew that
零所以 他们显然知道
it's so common to have so to off-by-one
它是如此常见的有这么 断接一个
bugs with strings where you don't
与字符串错误，你不
allocate enough space for the null
对于空分配足够的空间
terminator
终结者
that they said well rather than having a
他们说好，而不是一
canary that will detect that byte being
金丝雀， 将检测字节是
corrupted we'll just sort of give that
损坏我们就有点给 该
byte away and so that's why it's letting
字节 路程 ，所以这就是为什么它让
me type in eight characters and it's
我输入八个字符，它的
overriding this low order byte of the
压倒一切的这个低位字节
canary later on but that's not going to
金丝雀稍后但是这不会
affect anything
有 什么 影响
but let's give it 9 characters 10
但让我们给它9个字符10
characters to training a 9 character
字符训练的9个字符
string
串
Oh
哦
ah
啊
oh well I'm not finding it where I
哦，我没有找到它，我
thought it would be anyways oh this will
认为这将是 哦， 反正 这个意愿
crop this deck but what I is showing you
裁剪 此甲板，但我是你展示
the main idea is the canary some value
其主要 思想是金丝雀一定的 价值
that gets pulled out and it will vary
这被拔出，它会改变
from one time to the next and it's
从一次到 下一个，它的
letting you get away with eight
让你脱身八
characters plus the null terminator but
字符加上空终止 ，但
anything more and it will detect that
再说 了 ，它会检测
corruption
腐败
okay so now we've seen three different
好吧，现在我们已经看到了三种不同
protections well for one is write better
保护好一个是写出更好
code but there's three protections that
代码，但有三个防即
are done by the system that have nothing
通过什么 都没有 系统完成
to do with your code right one is to
做你的代码正确的是
randomize the stack position so it's
随机堆积 位置所以它的
harder to figure out where the start
很难 找出其中的开始
addresses are the second is to make the
地址是第二个是使
stack so it's not executable so you
栈，所以它不是可执行的，所以你
can't put code on that and then the
不能把代码上，然后
third is to use this deck canary or
第三是使用本甲板金丝雀或
other mechanisms to detect a potential
其他机制来检测潜在的
buffer overflow at the source so now
在源所以现在缓冲区溢出
there's another attack that was
还有，这是另一次攻击
developed in response to some of these
响应发展到其中的一些
that is still often successful it's
这仍然是经常成功的是
called return arted programming and for
所谓的回报arted编程和
your attack lab you're going to be doing
你的攻击实验中，您打算 做
these attacks too that's why the tackle
这些攻击过，这就是为什么解决
AB is different than the old way of the
AB比的旧的方式不同
old web justed code injection exploits
旧的Web justed代码注入漏洞
now you're doing both code injections
现在你在 做两个代码 注入
and return oriented programming so the
和返回导向编程使
idea this is if you are a hacker you're
这个想法是，如果你是你是一个黑客
frustrated because of these these three
沮丧，因为这些这三个
techniques stack randomization
技术 堆栈随机
non-executable stack and Canaries well I
非可执行堆栈和金丝雀我很好
can't fix the canary problem that
不能修复的金丝雀问题
actually the canary is a pretty secure
实际上金丝雀是一个非常安全的
of
的
technique there's very I've never seen
技术有很我从来没有见过
anyone able to bypass a stet canary but
任何人都可以绕过 STET金丝雀 但
the other two you can do it using this
另外两个，你可以用这个做
technique and the strategy is so we
技术和策略，所以我们
don't know where the stack is but we
不知道在哪里堆栈，但我们
could still but we know where the code
仍然但是我们知道在哪里的代码
is because you saw in that example the
是因为你在例子中看到的
code my layout randomization was
代码我的布局随机化
shifting the stack positions in the heap
移在堆栈位置
positions but it wasn't changing either
位置，但它并没有任何变化
global variables or or the code itself
全局变量或或代码本身
so what if I can find some code that
所以，如果我能找到什么一些代码，
sort of already there in the existing
的排序已经 存在 的现有
part of the program
该计划的一部分
and use that instead of my own code that
并使用我自己的代码 ， 而不是
I've injected and of course in general
我已经注入和一般课程
you're not going to find exactly lying
你不会 找到确切地躺在
there the exact program you want to
还有你要在严格程序
execute that will cause whatever harm
执行 将导致什么危害
you intend to do because it's not
你打算这样做，因为它不是
usually compiled into most programs but
通常编译成最的方案，但
if I could sort of string together
如果我能梳理串在一起
little segments of code and somehow put
代码段少，不知怎么放
together a series of little sequences of
在一起的一系列小序列的
code maybe I can get something useful
代码也许我可以得到一些有用的东西
done and so that's the idea of this
做，所以这是这个想法
return oriented programming and the idea
返回导向编程和想法
of it is to find what are known as
它是寻找所谓的
gadgets and a gadget is a sequence of
小工具和小 工具 是一个序列
bytes that are represent part of the
那些字节表示的部分
executable program where the last byte
可执行程序，其中最后一个字节
this is x86 talking here has a hex value
这是86讲在这里有一个十六进制值
c3 which is how the RET instruction the
C3这是怎么RET 指令
return instruction is encoded in x86
返回指令在编码的x86
both ia-32 and x64 and so as an example
两个IA-32和x64等作为 例子
on the easy case is where there's some
在简单的情况是有一些
function and it implements some
功能，它实现 了一些
operation that I might find useful as an
我可能会发现作为一个有用的操作
attacker to be able to do so for example
攻击者能够 例如这样做
this function is computing a times B
该功能 计算倍乙
plus C and if I look at just the last
加C，如果我看 刚刚过去的
two instructions from there one of them
从那里 他们 中的 一个两个指令
is a la which is performing addition and
被一拉被执行相加与
the other is doing a return so I can
另一种是做一回这样我就可以
think of this this good old five bunk
想到这本好老五铺位
byte chunk is a way if I could get some
字节块是一种方式，如果我能得到一些
data in registers R di and RDX then I
在寄存器R二和RDX然后数据I
could compute their sum and stick it in
可以计算它们的总和，并坚持在
the RAS so imagine taking your program
在RAS所以想象一下你的程序
you're trying to execute and breaking it
你想执行和打破它
up into these little fragments and you
成这些 小片段 ，你
want to somehow find little block of
要以某种方式找到的有点堵
code somewhere to implement each of
码的地方来实现各
these fragments and then the interesting
这些片段，然后有趣
part is because they each end in C 3
部分是因为它们在的C 3各端
this return as is it well let me get to
这个回报率是很好，让 我去
that
那
a minute so that's sort of the obvious
一分钟 ，这样的排序明显
way that you pull out this is an
你拉出来 这种 方式 是
addition which you'd expect because that
此外， 你会期望，因为 这
was in the original C code but here's an
在原来的C代码，但这里是一个
example of a gadget that has nothing to
例如一个小工具， 有 什么可
do with the original C code it just
做与原来 的 C代码，它只是
happens to match the bite pattern of
碰巧的咬模式 相匹配
some existing code so this function
一些现有的代码，所以此功能
seems to not do anything too terribly
似乎没有做任何事情太可怕
useful from hackers point of view but if
从黑客有用的角度来看，但如果
you look at this particular byte
你看看这个特定字节
sequence that happens to encode the
序列发生编码
instruction move Q are a X to R di and C
指令移动Q为一个 X至R二和C
3 encodes repped so and you can see if
3个编码repped所以，你可以看到，如果
this is at address 49 that's for D a for
这是地址49这对 D中 的
DB for DC so it address 400 for DC if
DB 直流所以解决 400如果DC
you could start executing here it would
你可以从这里开始执行，将
first do a move and then it would do a
首先做一个举动， 然后 它会做
return so I'm sort of taking advantage
返回所以我有点趁着
of the fact in x86 it says by doing it
在x86的事实，它说的 做
is instruction sequence and if I sort of
是，如果我有点指令序列和
go off the aligned instructions I can
熄灭对齐的指令，我可以
often find useful things to do so that's
经常会发现有用的东西，这样做，这是
what's called a gadget and you might ask
什么叫做小工具，你可能会问
well what's so special about having them
还有什么特别之处让他们
end in a return
结束返回
well imagine I could fill up my buffer
想像我可以填补我的缓冲区
instead of with executable code I could
而不是可执行代码我可以
fill it up with a series of gadget
一系列小工具的填充它
addresses so each gadget then is some
地址，以便每个小工具则是一些
series of bytes where the final bite is
一系列字节的，其中最终咬合是
c3 and I'll actually position this as
C3和我实际上这个位置作为
not the oppositionists at some place
不是反对派在一些地方
where you're actually going to do the
在那里你究竟要做到
initial return instruction of from from
从最初的返回指令
before so if I can somehow get the
之前， 所以如果 我能以某种方式获取
program to return execute a rest right
程序返回执行休息权
now what it will do is return will pick
现在它要做的是回归将挑
an address off of the stack pop an
从堆栈 弹出一个的地址
address and begin execute
地址并开始执行
so that will start this code executing
因此，将启动该代码执行
and it will hit the c3 the RET
它会击中 C3的RET
instruction at the end which will again
在结束指令其将再次
take a address pop it off the stack and
取地址弹出它从堆栈和
begin executing so start executing the
开始执行，从而开始执行
second gadget and so you'll see what
第二小工具，所以你会看到什么
will happen is we're effectively
将发生的情况 是，我们是有效的
concatenating these pieces of code
串联这些作品的代码
together where it's using a ret to get
如果加上它的使用RET得到
from one part the end of one gadget to
从一个第一部分的小工具的端部到
the start of the next and so that's
接下来的开始，因此这
what's called return oriented
什么叫做面向回报
programming to wait instead of
编程等 ， 而不是
sequencing programs using a program
使用程序测序计划
counter like you normally do your
计数器就像你通常做 你的
sequencing programs using the sort of
使用排序 的测序计划
peculiar behavior of this particular x86
这个特殊的x86的奇特行为
how returns work in in that program and
回报如何在程序中工作并
remember there's enough x86 out there
记得有足够的x86那里
that if I can find a way to attack them
如果我能找到一种方法来 攻击他们
I'm in pretty I'm in a pretty good place
我很漂亮，我在一个漂亮的好地方
it's also possible to attack other
它也可以攻击其他
processors this way - it's just
处理器这种方式 - 它只是
particularly nice on x86 so that's the
特别好的在x86所以这是
idea of return on in programming and
回报对编程思想和
you'll you'll do this yourself you'll
你会，你会做你自己，你会
find gadgets string them together to do
找到小工具 把它们串起来做
different things in the attack lamp but
在攻击 灯不同的东西，但
I'll point out that this still doesn't
我要指出的是，这还不
so that this stack canary idea is still
所以，这堆金丝雀想法还是
successful detecting a buffer overflows
成功检测到缓冲区溢出
fairly effectively so in your tack lab
相当有效地使你的粘性实验室
for example we've carefully compiled the
例如我们精心编制的
code to make it vulnerable to these
代码， 使其 容易受到这些
attacks otherwise it would be a lot
攻击否则这将是 一个很大
harder web like if you could do this you
更难的网络一样，如果你能 做到这一点，你
could probably go into the dark world
很可能进入 黑暗的世界
and and be very successful so but so
和和是非常成功的，但如此如此
we're actually sort of exposing the
我们实际上有点暴露
vulnerability but in the the first part
漏洞，但在第一部分
of the lab you're using code injection
该实验室的你使用代码注入
attacks so we've had to disable stack
攻击所以我们不得不禁用堆栈
randomization and also make the stack X
随机化，也使组X
cutable so we had to sort of button the
可切割，所以我们不得不进行排序 按钮的
return on programming we reenable that
回报规划，我们认为重新启用
so that the stack is not executable it
从而使堆栈不可执行它
keeps jumping around randomly up but
不断随机 跳来跳去 了，但
we've turned off the stack Canaries so
我们已经关闭了堆栈加那利群岛这样
you'll be able to overflow the buffer
你就可以溢出缓冲区
and put in your gadget addresses and
并把你的小工具地址，
build up a text that way so I think
建立了这种方式 ，所以我觉得 一个文本
you'll find by actually doing it you'll
您将通过实际 去做，你会 发现
learn a lot more than you can by just
学习 比你可以通过只 多 了很多
hearing about it oh you might ask why do
听到 这种 事情 ， 哦，你可能会问为什么
we teach you this stuff right and if we
我们教你这个东西的权利，如果我们
supposed to teach you to be good and not
应该教你是好事，而不是
evil well there's a couple reasons one
邪恶的以及有一对夫妇的原因之一
is you're going to learn a lot about
是你会学到很多
machine program execution and how stacks
机程序的执行以及如何堆栈
work and how byte instructions are
工作和如何字节指令
encoded and stuff like that you'll use
编码和类似的东西，你会使用
the tools gb object dump and all those
该工具GB对象转储和所有那些
even more than you did with the bomb web
甚至比你做了与炸弹 网页
so you'll learn a lot the other is we
所以你会学到很多东西， 另一个 是我们
assume that you will work for forces of
假设你会为部队工作
good but to be a good person you also
很好，但是是一个很好的人，你也
know what the bet have to know what the
知道什么 赌注必须知道什么
bad people do so part of it is to become
坏人做它的一部分 是成为
more effective as a force for good okay
更有效的为善的力量好
so the final thing to talk about today
所以最后一件事说说今天
is unions and the observation about a
是工会和有关观察
union in C is the declaration that it
用C工会的声明，它
looks a lot like a struct where there's
看起来很像一个struct那里的
this different fields and they're named
这种 不同的领域，他们命名
and they can have different types and
他们可以有不同的类型和
there can be pointers to unions and all
可以有指向工会和所有
that stuff but they're actually totally
那东西，但 它们实际上是完全
different what they do you recall it a
不同的他们你还记得 它
struct what happens as it Ella Cates
结构，因为它埃拉·卡茨会发生什么
enough memory for all the fields to
足够的内存为 所有领域
coexist and potentially adding padding
共存并潜在地添加填充
bytes for what a union does is it only K
什么工会 所做的就是只有千 字节
allocates enough storage for the maximum
分配足够的存储空间最大
field in it and it assumes that you're
领域它，它假设你
only going to be using one of the
只有将要使用的一个
possible fields and it will literally a
可能的领域，它会 从字面上
store on top of these fields get stored
在这些领域的顶级商店获取存储
on top of each other so that if you
在彼此的顶部，这样 ，如果你
try to use multiple fields you can mess
尝试使用多个字段，你可以乱
things up
事情
and it's not for that purpose of doing
这不是做的这个目的
multiple values it's for the purpose of
多个值是为目的
for example if I know I'm only going to
例如，如果我知道我只打算
use one of these or it's another also a
使用 其中的一个 或它的 另一个也是一个
way to create essentially an alias that
方法基本上创建一个别名
will let you reference memory in
会让你在引用内存
different ways so for example in your
不同的方式，使例如在您
data web viewer using you were
数据网络浏览器使用你
manipulating the bit level
操纵位水平
representations of floating point
浮点交涉
numbers and in our code that would then
数字和我们的代码，然后将
convert that to an actual float we used
将其转换成我们使用 的实际浮动
a union where the Union is either to
工会在 联盟要么
view this field of four bytes is an
查看的四个字节这个字段是一个
unsigned or is a float and so I can
无符号或是一个浮子，所以我可以
convert from unsigned to its float
从无符号转换成 其浮动
representation by just storing the
通过仅存储表示
unsigned value in this Union and
在这个联盟无符号值和
retrieving it as if it were float and
检索它，就好像它是浮动和
this is a fundamentally different
这是一个根本不同
operation than casting because you
操作比铸造 ，因为你
recall when you take an unsigned value
还记得当你把 一个无符号值
and you cast it to a float you actually
你将它转换为一个浮动你实际上
change the bit to change it into the
改位，改变成的
floating point number that the closest a
浮点数是 最接近的 一个
match to this particular number it would
符合这一特定数量会
be the equivalent of the function you
是功能相当于你
implemented float underscore you to F
实行浮动下划线 你到F
but this one actually doesn't change
但是这一次实际上不会改变
bits it just changes the numeric value
位，它只是改变 了数值
changes quite a bit so it's a useful
改变颇有几分所以这是一个非常有用
technique to do that to be able to
技术要 去做那些能够
override the the type system and get to
覆盖类型系统 ， 并获得
representations and this actually turns
表示 这实际上变成
out to be one of the places to where
出是地方 的 地方 之一
byte ordering will show up in programs
字节顺序将在计划显示
if you're not careful so in particular
如果你不小心， 特别 是
with this Union I can view a block of
这个联盟，我可以查看块
eight bytes as either eight characters
八个字节为任一八个字符
for shorts to inch through one long and
为短裤通过一个长和英寸
on a 64-bit machine like is shown here
在64位机器上像在此示出
where along is 64 bits you'll see that
其中一起 是64位 ，你会看到，
you're you're able to
你是你能
get things as either as a the individual
让事情无论是作为个人
bites making it up or some longer
叮咬补差或更长一些
aggregation of those bytes and you'll
这些 字节的聚集，你会
actually find that depending on what
实际上发现， 取决于 什么
machine you run it on you'll get a
机器运行它，你会得到一个
different result because of the byte
不同的结果，因为字节
ordering of the different machines so
不同机器的顺序，使
this goes through it what happens when
这个经过它时 会发生什么
you run on different machines
你在不同的机器上运行
but you'll you'll notice in particular
但你会，你会特别注意
that on a thirty-two machine a 32-bit
一个 32机 上 的32位的
machine it's coming off in in this byte
机 它的脱落，在此 字节
pattern F 3 F 2 F 1 F 0 and on a Sun
图案F 3 F 2 F 1个F 0 和在Sun
back when they existed you'd get the
回来时，他们的存在，你会得到
opposite becomes in the byte ordering
相反成为字节顺序
and now on an x86 64 where a long is 64
现在在x86 64，在一个长为64
bits you get a 8 byte and you can also
位你得到一个8字节，你也可以
determine from this if you look
从这个判断，如果你看
carefully that it's in it's a little
小心，它在它的一点点
endian order because this is the least
endian顺序，因为这是最
significant byte is F 0 which is the
显著字节为 F 0，这是
first byte f0 so it's also a way to get
第一个字节F0 所以它也是一种 方式来 获得
to the low level bytes but when you use
低电平字节，但是当你使用
this kind of thing you're sort of
这种 事情你是那种
intentionally telling the the C compiler
故意告诉C编译器
trust me I know what I'm doing you don't
相信我，我知道 我在做什么你 不
have to protect me from myself and so if
要保护我快乐所以如果
you're not careful you can write code
你不小心，你 可以编写代码
where because of a byte ordering problem
其中， 因为字节顺序问题
or something like that
或 类似的 东西
won't run properly on some machines so
不会 在一些机器上 正常运行 ，从而
just to summarize then we looked on it
只是总结那么，我们看着它
we've looked down at the three compound
我们已经在三个复合放在眼里
types in C the ways you can aggregate
类型C，可聚合的方法
smaller types into larger ones you can
较小的类型成大即可
make an array of identical elements
使相同 的元件 的阵列
indexed by a number the position and
由多个位置索引，并
that usually turns into some kind of
通常变成某种
scaled computation to get to the
按比例计算得到的
particular place we've seen structures
我们所看到的结构特别的地方
where it's a fixed number of fields but
它是一个固定数量的字段，但
the fields can be of different type and
该字段可以是不同的 类型和
the reference by their names and that
通过他们的名字和参考
usually turns into some type of
通常变成某种类型的
it's placement off of the original
它的位置 离原来的
position and then a union is just a way
位置，然后工会只是一种方式
of sort of piling up in one place of
在一个地方的 那种 堆砌
what a number of different fields and so
什么是许多不同的领域等等
all it does delegate the maximum number
所有它委托的最大数量
of bytes for that and doesn't create
的字节为，并且不产生
enough space for them all to be there at
足够的空间，他们都 在那里，在
the same time okay that's it for today
同时 还行就是这样今天
[Applause]
[掌声]